<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOME on Daniele Caschili</title>
    <link>https://dcaschili.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HOME on Daniele Caschili</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://dcaschili.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Snake</title>
      <link>https://dcaschili.github.io/personal/snake/snake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dcaschili.github.io/personal/snake/snake/</guid>
      <description>This is a snake clone that I made in Unreal Engine 5 to improve my knowledge of the engine.
I uploaded a small gameplay video here.
Main features:
Grass rendering + grass blades bending Niagara: Snake body -&amp;gt; ribbon Grass bending direction Enhanced input Savegame system for tracking player record. Materials: Grass checkerboard pattern and fake AO Snake body color In addition I added some visual debugging features, like snake body box colliders and tile occupancy to help me during development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EngineGL</title>
      <link>https://dcaschili.github.io/personal/enginegl/enginegl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dcaschili.github.io/personal/enginegl/enginegl/</guid>
      <description>This is a toy renderer written in C++ and OpenGL to learn new graphics techniques and C++. The renderer features at the moment:
Forward rendering Spot and directional lights support Shadowmapping Soft edge shadows Shadow support for multiple lights Environment mapping + simple environment reflections. Soft shadows To add soft shadows I implemented the technique described in GPU Gems 2 ch. 17.
Basically it adds some noise to offset the sample points for the PCF technique.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ray Marched scene</title>
      <link>https://dcaschili.github.io/personal/raymarchedscene/raymarchedscene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dcaschili.github.io/personal/raymarchedscene/raymarchedscene/</guid>
      <description>This is a basic shader created in Shadertoy to learn and explore ray marching. In this project, I implemented the following features:
Signed distance field to render spheres and a plane. A simple Blinn-Phong lighting model with a directional light. Shadows achieved by ray marching towards the light source. </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
